ACHYUTANANDA NAYAK

Software Developer Engineer - 1



SUMMARY

As an experienced web developer with 1 plus years in the field, I have a strong understanding of modern web technologies like JavaScript, TypeScript with Frameworks such as React JS, Node JS, Angular, AntD, HTML5 and CSS3. I am experienced in developing and deploying microservices. I am passionate about staying up-to-date with industry trends and exploring new tools and techniques to improve my craft.

EDUCATION

Degree: B.Tech in Computer Science & Engineering

Silicon Institute of Technology, Bhubaneswar 2018 - 2022

EXPERIENCE

Software Developer Engineer

Propelld 07/2022 - Ongoing Bengaluru

Propelld is an Indian fintech & edtech company that offers education loans to students who wish to pursue higher education in India or abroad.

- . Have an opportunity to work on 8 dashboards & also taking ownership on some of
- · Creating and implementing responsive design and optimization technologies.
- Working on microservices from back-end which helps me to proceed as a fullstack developer.
- Mentoring junior developers and overseeing their professional development.
- Participating in code reviews and ensuring that the code adheres to industry standards and best practices.

Software Developer Intern

Propelld 01/2022 - 06/2022 Bengaluru

Propelld is an Indian fintech & edtech company that offers education loans to students who wish to pursue higher education in India or abroad.

- Manage application development project from initial designs through completion.
- Collaborating with designers, back-end developers and stakeholders to create seamless user experiences.
- Worked single handedly on a MVP(Minimum viable product) project from the front-end side & delivered it on time.
- Moved most of the microservices to API-Gateway.
- Keeping up to date with the latest web development trends and technologies.
- · Troubleshooting and debugging code and resolving issues that may arise.

LANGUAGES

English	Proficient	Odia	Native
Hindi	Proficient		

SKILLS

TypeScript		JavaScript		Ang	Angular	
React	JS	Redux	Nod	le JS	MEAN	
MERN	Aı	ntD _	Flask	Мо	ngo DB	
Git	Git GitLab		itBucke	et		

PROJECTS

Life Expectancy Prediction

- This project will basically give a prediction about the life expectancy to the users by enquiring some data from them.
- So there are 22 fields where user need to give some information then we are using a specified model in our backend side to predict according to it.
- So for front-end we are using Flask & for back-end there are python & ML models.

NEWS API/COVID Tracker

- This is a news web application .In which user can able to read latest news about technology or many other things.
- The major things is there is an option for covidtracker which will give current information about the covid about all the countries.
- Here for the front-end development I am using Angular, TypeScript & for back-end side there is Node|S.

PASSIONS

Continuous learning

Collaboration

User experience

co Gaming